A Guide to the Alexander Wilbourne Weddell papers, 1888-1947
Virginia Historical Society, Richmond, Va.
Anderson, Henry W. (Henry Watkins), 1870-1954; Astor, Nancy Witcher Langhorne Astor, Viscountess, 1879-1964; Bottomley, William Lawrence, 1883-1951; Bruce, William Cabell, 1860-1946; Bryan, John Stewart, 1871-1944; Bryan, Jonathan; Byrd, Harry F. (Harry Flood), 1887-1966; Carr, Wilbur John, 1870-1942; Coolidge, Calvin, 1872-1933; Darden, Colgate W. (Colgate Whitehead), 1897-1981; Dugdale, Elizabeth Cabell, 1902-1990; Ellyson, Lora Effie Hotchkiss, 1848-1935; Glasgow, Ellen Anderson Gholson, 1873-1945; Glass, Carter, 1858-1946; Harding, Warren G. (Warren Gamaliel), 1865-1923; Hull, Cordell, 1871-1955; Lane, Arthur Bliss, 1894–1956; Montague, Andrew Jackson, 1862-1937; Morrow, Dwight W. (Dwight Whitney), 1873-1931; Morse, Henry Grant, 1884-1934; Olds, Robert Edwin, 1875-1932; Page, Thomas Nelson, 1853-1922; Pollard, John Garland, 1871-1937; Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1884-1962; Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945; Sheffield, James Rockwell, 1864–1938; Swanson, Claude Augustus, 1862-1939; Taft, William H. (William Howard), 1857-1930; Templewood, Samuel John Gurney Hoare, Viscount, 1880-1959; Weddell, Alexander Watson, 1841-1883; Weddell, Alexander Wilbourne, 1876-1948; Weddell, Elizabeth Wright, 1878-1955; Weddell, James, 1807-1865; Weddell, Margaret Ward, 1869-1935; Weddell, Penelope Margaret Wright, 1840-1901; Weddell, Virginia Chase Steedman, 1874-1948; Weddell, William Sparrow, 1874-1944; Welles, Sumner, 1892-1961; Williams, John L. (John Langbourne), 1831-1915; Williams, John Skelton, 1865-1926; Wilson, Woodrow, 1856-1924
Family Names:
Weddell family Genealogy; Wright family Genealogy
Corporate Names:
Protestant Episcopal Church Home for Ladies (Richmond, Va.)
Subjects:
American Red Cross; Argentina Diplomats United States; Argentina Foreign relations United States; Autobiography; Catania (Italy); Charities Virginia Richmond History 20th century; Copenhagen (Denmark); Denmark Foreign relations United States; Diplomatic and consular service, American; Diplomatic and consular service United States History 20th century; Greece Foreign relations United States; India Foreign relations United States; Italy Foreign relations United States; Mexico Foreign relations United States; Richmond Community Fund (Richmond, Va.); Southern Churchman; Spain Foreign relations United States; United States. Consulate (Athens, Greece); United States. Consulate (Calcutta, India); United States. Consulate (Catania, Italy); United States. Consulate (Mexico City, Mexico); United States. Consulate (Zanzibar, Zanzibar); United States. Department of State; United States Diplomatic and consular service History 20th century; United States Foreign relations Argentina; United States Foreign relations Denmark; United States Foreign relations Greece; United States Foreign relations India; United States Foreign relations Italy; United States Foreign relations Mexico; United States Foreign relations Spain; United States Foreign relations Zanzibar; United States. General and Special Claims Commissions; Virginia House (Richmond, Va.); Virginia Museum of Fine Arts; Virginians Argentina; Virginians Mexico; Women's Council of the Navy League of the United States; Zanzibar; Zanzibar Foreign relations United States
Contents List
- Series 1. Weddell family papers, 1858-1925
  - Subseries 1.1. James Weddell (1807-1865) (Box 1)
    - Estate accounts, 1865
  - Subseries 1.2. Rev. Alexander Watson Weddell (1841-1883) (Box 1)
    - Honorary degree, sermons, notes, news clippings; scrapbook; obituary notices
  - Subseries 1.3. Penelope Margaret Wright Weddell (1840-1901)
    - Reminiscence, 1895, of the Fall of Richmond in 1865; letters of condolence, 1901; administrator’s records, 1901; miscellany, 1858-1925 (Box 1)
- Series 2. Alexander Wilbourne and Virginia Weddell, 1876-1948
  - Subseries 2.1. Diaries/calendars, 1907-1947 (Box 1-3)
    - Diaries, 1907-1913; 1915-1916; 1919-1947 (36 vols.); desk calendars, 1947
  - Subseries 2.2. Correspondence, 1883-1947 (Box 4-15)
  - Subseries 2.3. Correspondence, 1923-1946, with Virginia (Chase) Steedman Weddell (Box 15)
  - Subseries 2.4. Financial Records, 1897-1947 (Box 16-29)
    - Personal account book, Loose accounts, book/manuscript orders, monthly expense sheets/petty cash, investment/ banking records, and income tax records
  - Subseries 2.5. Miscellaneous, 1899-1946 (Box 30)
    - Educational records, scrapbooks, marriage to Virginia (Chase) Steedman
  - Subseries 2.6. Diplomatic Service Files, 1908-1942 (Box 30-34a)
    - American legation, Copenhagen, Denmark; American Consul, Zanzibar; American Consul, Catania, Italy; American Consul general, Athens, Greece; American Consulate, Calcutta, India; American Consulate, Mexico City, Mexico; Ambassador to Argentina; Ambassador to Spain; and calling cards.
  - Subseries 2.7. Organization and Association files, 1923-1948 (Box 35-41)
  - Subseries 2.8. Speeches, Addresses, and publications, 1930-1947 (Box 41-48)
  - Subseries 2.9. Virginia House, 1925-1947 (Box 49-50)
  - Subseries 2.10. Miscellaneous, 1929-1948 (Box 50-51)
- Series 3. Virginia (Chase) Steedman Weddell, 1866-1947
  - Subseries 3.1. Diaries, 1922-1923 (Box 52)
  - Subseries 3.2. Correspondence, 1866-1947 (Box 52-53)
  - Subseries 3.3. Financial and Philanthropy, 1923-1955 (Box 53)
    - Loose accounts, Commonplace books, address books, land records, presentation at Court of St. James, passport, relief work
  - Subseries 3.4. James Harrison Steedman estate files, 1895-1945 (Box 54)
  - Subseries 3.5. Miscellaneous (Box 55)
    - Speeches, memberships, Christmas cards, news clippings, recipe book, personal miscellany
- Series 4. Family Miscellaneous
  - Miscellany of Weddell sisters, genealogical materials, hereditary patriotic societies (Box 55)